Mateeb Alharbi

Frontend Developer

Mateeb2000@gmail.com

966560046457

mateeb.com

linkedin.com/in/mateeb-alharbi

github.com/Mateeb11 🦪

A fresh Computer Science graduate, and a Front-end web developer using React and Angular. My Passion is to build modern and responsive websites. As a Frontend developer, I'm interested in the UX/UI field and how to improve the user experience, so that I can learn how to implement new ideas and user experience.

EDUCATION

O Bachelor - Computer Science Umm AL-Qura University

05/2018 - 06/2023

3.71 / 4 GPA with second honors

PROJECTS

Multi-step form (05/2023 - 05/2023)

- A frontend mentor challenge for a multi-step form, the form have input validation and feedbacks. The website is responsive for all screen sizes. Made with React, Sass (preprocessor scripting language that is interpreted or compiled into CSS). All the CSS is done by me and I didn't use any library or framework.
- Try it here: https://aback-icicle.surge.sh
- https://github.com/Mateeb11/multi-step-form

Easybank landing page (04/2023 - 05/2023)

- A frontend mentor challenge for building a landing page for a company, the website is responsive for all screen sizes. Made with React, Sass. All the CSS is done by me and I didn't use any library or framework.
- Try it here: https://gifted-selection.surge.sh
- https://github.com/Mateeb11/easybank-landing-page-master

REST Countries API with color theme switcher (04/2023 - 04/2023)

- A frontend mentor challenge for a website that fetches data from REST API about countries. Also, it has dark and light mode switching. Made with react, react-router-dom, and redux-toolkit.
- Try it here: https://humdrum-smell.surge.sh
- https://shorturl.at/clsw2

EXPERIENCE

Elite Specialist | Tech GDP

Mobily

06/2024 - Present Riyadh

Junior Software Engineer

WAKI

11/2023 - 06/2024 Jeddah

Junior Software Developer

Misk traineeship program at WAKI

08/2023 - 10/2023 Jeddah

IOT and software development

Smart Methods · Internship الأساليب الذكية

06/2022 - 08/2022 Makkah

TECHNICAL SKILLS



SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork, Problem Solving, Communication, Self Management, Creativity, Willing to Learn.

CERTIFICATES

Misk skills - Nanodegree Program - Intro To Programming (04/2020 - 05/2020) At Udacity

INTERESTS

Web Development Machine Learning

UX/UI Design